

SYAFAAT DEHA FEBRIYAN

089501503811 | syafaat.deha12@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/syafaatdehafebriyan/ | https://syafaatdehaf.github.io/syafaatdehaf/

Kota Tangerang

Hello, I am a graduate of Telecommunication Engineering at Telkom University. As an individual with technical expertise in networking, cybersecurity and telecommunications. In addition to technical expertise, I have the skills for analytical thinking, communication, and the ability to do creative things.

Work Experiences

PT. Datacomm Diangraha - Jakarta, Indonesia

Oct 2023 - Present

IT Security Analyst

PT Datacomm Diangraha is the leading Information Technology (IT) service providers in Indonesia with focus in the following areas: IT Infrastructure, Cloud & Datacenter, IT Security, and DevOps.

- Perform daily monitoring on information security events, incidents, and vulnerabilities. Perform L1 incident response and troubleshooting.
- · Create daily, weekly, and monthly reports to analyze suspicious activity and detail potential attacks detected.
- Use SIEM to analyze security data from various sources, including system logs and network activity, identify threat patterns, detect
 ongoing attacks, and respond quickly.

Telkom Univeristy - Bandung, West Java. Indonesia

Sep 2022 - Jul 2023

Researcher Capstone Design

- Conducted focused research on Named Data Networking (NDN), a future internet architecture.
- Performed in-depth research on packet forwarding in Named Data Network (NDN), with a particular focus on identifying and analyzing the most optimal packet forwarding performance.
- Successfully published articles in Indonesia's SINTA-accredited journals and IEEE Xplore conference papers, demonstrating our commitment to this research.

Adaptive Network Laboratory - Telkom University, West Java,

Oct 2021 - Jun 2023

Bandung. Indonesia

Practicum Assistant

- Instructed over 350 students in telecommunications engineering, delivering comprehensive lessons on topics such as computer network fundamentals, various routing protocols, Linux basics, Wireshark, and QoS parameter calculations.
- Assumed a pivotal role in the Practicum Strategy Division, orchestrating the coordination and execution of diverse practicum activities.
- Explored various aspects of technology, including Linux, Docker, Kubernetes, and Software Defined Networking (SDN).

PT Telkom Indonesia (Persero) Tbk - West Java, Bandung.

Jul 2022 - Aug 2022

Indonesia

Internship

PT Telkom Indonesia (Persero) Tbk , Access Optima & Construction SPV Division

- Maintain and expand FTTH (Fiber to the Home) networks, ensuring seamless connectivity and high-quality service delivery to customers.
- Maintain OLT (Optical Line Terminal) and ODP (Optical Distribution Point) in various areas of Bandung.
- In addition to my role in the Access Optima & Construction SPV Division, I was also assigned to the Survey Drawing & Inventory Division, where I was responsible for repairing ODP (Optical Distribution Point) using the provided website.

PT Telkom Indonesia (Persero) Tbk - Tangerang, Indonesia

Sep 2018 - Nov 2018

Internship

PT Telkom Indonesia (Persero) Tbk , IT Support Division

- Installation and Configuration: Install, configure, and maintain hardware and software, including operating systems, applications, and network devices.
- · Provided essential technical support by promptly identifying and resolving computer issues to ensure smooth operations.
- Required knowledge in configuring Local Area Networks (LAN) across multiple computers, optimizing network speed, and ensuring
 efficient data exchange.

Education Level

Telkom University - West Java, Bandung. Indonesia

Sep 2019 - Aug 2023

Bachelor of Telecommunication Enggineer, 3.20/4.00

 Developed and carried out a thorough research project termed "NDN HIGHSPEED" with the goal of improving understanding and usability of Named Data Network (NDN) technology. Named Data Network a future internet architecture

SMK Telkom Jakarta - West Jakarta, DKI Jakarta. Indonesia

Sep 2016 - Aug 2019

High School Diploma in Computer Systems Network and Telecommunication

 Actively participated in practical exercises involving Cisco Packet Tracers, acquiring a practical understanding of network configuration, troubleshooting and fiber optic.

Organisational Experience

HMTT Telco TEL-U - West Java, Bandung. Indonesia

Jun 2022 - May 2023

Bureau of Entrepreneurship Department

• The Entrepreneurship Department Bureau has the responsibility to supervise or ensure that all staff in the Entrepreneurship Department have a good relationship.

HMTT Telco TEL-U - West Java, Bandung. Indonesia

Apr 2021 - May 2022

Senior Staff of Entrepreneurship Department

• The senior staff of the entrepreneurship department has the responsibility to provide the funds that HMTT will need and conduct various innovations in entrepreneurship.

HMTT Telco TEL-U - West Java, Bandung. Indonesia

Feb 2021 - Apr 2021

Junior Staff of Entrepreneurship Department

• Junior staff of the entrepreneurship department conduct an introduction to the department that has the responsibility to provide the funds that HMTT will need.

Skills, Achievements & Other Experience

- Hard Skills: Microsoft Office(Word, Excel, Power Point), Cisco Packet Tracers, PNETLab, Linux, Wireshark, Virtual Machine, SIEM (Security Information and Event Management)
- · Soft Skills: Time Management, Good Communication, Problem Solving, Adapt to the Environment.
- Projects ② (2023): Published a Sinta journal entitled "Interoperability of NDN-DPDK and Forwarding NFD in NDN-based Video
 Streaming on Virtual Machine" and Published an Conference IEEE Xplore paper entitled "Evaluating The Implementation of NFD, MW-NFD, and YaNFD in NDN-Based Video Streaming System".